[
  {
    "question": "How many functional tram cars does the BVG ('Berliner Verkehrsgesellschaft', the Berlin local traffic company) own?",
    "answer": 600,
    "hints": [
      "In 2018, the BVG was transporting 204 million guests.",
      "In 1990, the BVG owned 1024 tram cars."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["Berlin", "public transportation"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the amount of cash US $ in circulation? [in billions]",
    "answer": 800,
    "hints": [
      "Every day, 16 million 1$-notes are printed and destroyed.",
      "A US-$-note is in circulation for about 20 months."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["USA", "finance", "economy"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many Rolls Royce cars have been sold in 2019?",
    "answer": 5100,
    "hints": [
      "The price of the Rolls Royce Phantom, Rolls Royce's most sold car, starts from about 450.000 €.",
      "In 2007, Rolls Royce sold 1100 cars."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["UK", "Europe", "luxury", "economy"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many popes have there ever been (as counted by the catholic church)?",
    "answer": 266,
    "hints": [
      "The apostle St. Peter is considerd the first pope.",
      "Pius IX was the pope with the longest pontificate, being in office for 31 years, 7 months and 23 days."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["religion", "history", "Europe"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many inhabitants does Bangladesh have as of 2020? (in millions)",
    "answer": 164.7,
    "hints": [
      "1969, Bangladesh had 62.68 million inhabitants.",
      "The density of population in Bangladesh was 1,116.1 inhabitants per square kilometer as of 2020."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["population", "Bangladesh", "Asia", ""]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the height of Angela Merkel? (in cm)",
    "answer": 165,
    "hints": [
      "Donald Trump is 190 cm high.",
      "The average height of german women in the age between 18 and 40 is 166 cm."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["Germany", "politics"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which walking pace is assumed for pedestrians when programming the duration of green phases at traffic lights in Germany? [in km/h]",
    "answer": 4.32,
    "hints": [
      "Unhurried strolling has a walking pace of about 3 km/h.",
      "The average pace of a pedestrian is about 5 km/h."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": []
  },
  {
    "question": "How many WhatsApp messages are sent per second? [as of June 2020]",
    "answer": 750000,
    "hints": [
      "WhatsApp is the most used messenger app on the globe.",
      "As of June 2020, there have been 2 billion WhatsApp users around the globe."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": []
  },
  {
    "question": "How many women are elected head of government (i.e. holding office of the Prime Minister or comparable office)? [as of September 1st 2020]",
    "answer": 15,
    "hints": [
      "2015 we were living under a record-high number of simultanious female world leaders.",
      "Totally, 42 women have ever been heads of government."
    ],
    "explanation": "The full list is (ordered by length of duration in office): Angela Merkel (Germany), Sheikh Hasina (Bangladesh), Erna Solberg (Norway), Saara Kuugongelwa (Namibia), Aung San Suu Kyi (Myanmar), Tsai Ing-wen (Republic of China [Taiwan]), Ana Brnabić (Serbia), Jacinda Ardern (New Zealand), Katrín Jakobsdóttir (Iceland), Mia Mottley (Barbados), Mette Frederiksen (Denmark), Jeanine Áñez (Bolivia), Sanna Marin (Finland), Rose Christiane Raponda (Gabon), Victoire Tomegah Dogbé (Togo)",
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["politics", "feminism"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many black actors or actresses have been winning an Academy Award as Best Actor or Best Actress in a Leading Role? [as of 2019]",
    "answer": 5,
    "hints": [
      "In 2019, the 91st Academy Awards ceremony has been held.",
      "The number can be counted by one hand."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": []
  },
  {
    "question": "How long was the longest movie winning an Oscar for Best Picture? [in minutes]",
    "answer": 238,
    "hints": [
      "The longest movie to win an Oscar was 'War and Peace' and lasted 431 minutes.",
      "The longest movie winning an Oscar for Best Picture is 1939's 'Gone with the Wind'."
    ],
    "explanation": "Gone with the Wind, 1939",
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["culture", "movie", "duration"]
  },
  {
    "question": "In how many general elections did Queen Elizabeth II participate?",
    "answer": 0,
    "hints": [
      "Queen Elizabeth II was born on 21 April 1926",
      "There is nothing in written British law barring Queen Elizabeth II from voting in an election."
    ],
    "explanation": "Although not prohibited by law, it is considered unconstitutional for the Monarch to vote in an election.",
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["politics", "history", "UK", "Europe"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many years since the Nobel Peace Prize exists, has it not been awarded? [as of 2019]",
    "answer": 19,
    "hints": [
      "In total, there are 134 Nobel Peace Prize Laureates.",
      "The Nobel Peace Prize exists since 1901."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["history", "politics"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How long is the German Highway ('Autobahn') net? [in km]",
    "answer": 12993,
    "hints": [
      "The longest German highway is the Autobahn A7, with a length of 962 km.",
      "The 1974 album \"Autobahn\" from the band Kraftwerk made it to made it number five on the US billboard charts."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["Germany", "public transportation"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the beer consumption per year per capita in the United States? (as of 2019) [in litres]",
    "answer": 73.5,
    "hints": [
      "The country with the highest beer consumption per capita is the Czech Republic, with 191.8 litres.",
      "In 2010, the US consumption of pure alcohol per year per capita was 9.2 litres."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["USA"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many human beings (homo sapiens sapiens) have ever lived on earth (in total)? [in billions]",
    "answer": 108,
    "hints": [
      "Modern homo sapiens sapiens first walked the earth about 50,000 years ago.",
      "The current human population is about 7 billion."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["biology", "history", "population"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many pigs have been slaughtered in Germany in 2019?",
    "answer": 55000000,
    "hints": [
      "In 2019, Germany has produced 119 % of the number of pigs sold on the domestic market.",
      "In 2019, 20,575 goats have been slaughtered in Germany."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["Germany", "food", "consumption"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many police officers Berlin does Berlin have? (as of 2019)",
    "answer": 17000,
    "hints": [
      "As of 2019, Germany had a total of 319,400 police officers.",
      "In 2018, 748,000 police-patrol-car actions have been carried out."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["Germany", "police", "politics"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many babies have been born in Germany in 2019?",
    "answer": 778090,
    "hints": [
      "In 1990, 830019 babies have been born in Germany.",
      "The number is lower for 2019 than for 1990."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["Germany", "population"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many cells are in a chicken-egg?",
    "answer": 1,
    "hints": [
      "The yellow of the egg weighs about 30% of the egg.",
      "Think twice."
    ],
    "explanation": "As long as the egg is not fertilized, it's just the ovule.",
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["biology"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many people live in Africa? (as of 2020) [in millions]",
    "answer": 1216,
    "hints": [
      "Nigeria, the biggest African country by population, has about 206 million inhabitants.",
      "Europe has about 741 million inhabitants."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": ["Africa", "population"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2020 season of the Bachelorette features Clare Crawley, the oldest Bachelorette in the show's history. How old is she?",
    "answer": 39,
    "hints": [
      "After just two weeks Clare stopped shooting cause she was already in love with Dale. She was replaced with 9 years younger Tayshia Adams.",
      "After getting kicked out by Clare, Yosef yelled \"I expected way more from the OLDEST BACHELORETTE IN HISTORY!\" and \"Remember, you're almost 40!\"."
    ],
    "language": "en",
    "tags": []
  }
]
